SOPE KETIKU

FULL STACK-WEB DEVELOPER



www.linkedin.com/in/sope-ketiku



07767178169



ketikusope@gmail.com



https://ksopedev-site.netlify.app/



Manchester, U.K. (Have right to work in the U.K.)

EDUCATION

Feb, 2023 - Till Date

CAREERFOUNDRY BOOTCAMP PROGRAM Full-Stack Web Development

PROJECTS

myFlix API

TECHNOLOGIES:

HTML, JavaScript, MongoDB, Mongoose, Passport, Postman, Express, Node.js

Challenge: I built the server-side component of a "movies" web application where web applications can plug in to provide users with access to information about different movies, directors, and genres.

myFlix React App

TECHNOLOGIES:

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React Bootstrap, React, Redux, Parcel Challenge: Using React, I built a single-page application (SPA) which served as the client-side of a "movies" web application. Styling was done using React Bootstrap, while Redux was used for State Management.

React Native Mobile Chat App

TECHNOLOGIES:

JavaScript, React Native, Firebase, FireStore, Expo Go, Android Emulator

Challenge: Using *Expo CLI* and *React Native*, I built a mobile chat app with a customised interface for the chat screen and additional communication features such as sending images and location data. All data is stored online and offline.

2005 - 2007

UNIVERSITY OF SALFORD, U.K.

M.Sc Computer Science

1995 - 2001

UNIVERSITY OF LAGOS, NIGERIA

BArch Architecture

SUMMARY

Web developer with a background in building architecture, software testing, eLearning and a past experience in helping start-ups build teams and interface with clients to turn requirements into final products. Will bring innovative thinking, willingness to learn and design background in helping build responsive applications from idea to launch and committed to being a reliable and collaborative team player.

SKILLS

- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Typescript,
- Libraries/Frameworks (React, Redux, Material, Bootstrap, jQuery, SASS, SCSS and Angular
- Node.js and Express
- REST APIs, Postman
- MongoDB & PostgreSQL
- Business Logic using Mongoose
- Google OAuth and JWT tokenbased authentication
- Hosting and Web Services (AWS, Google FireStore, Heroku and Netlify, Google API console
- Version Control (Git)
- Mobile Apps (React Native, PWA, Expo
- Test Driven Development
- JSDocs and TypeDocs

EXPERIENCE

LEAD BUILDING DESIGN ARCHITECT/ HEAD, CONSTRUCTION PROJECT TEAM

BrundtLand Projects Limited, Lagos, Nigeria

Aug 2011 - Jun 2023

- Founded a design and build company which entailed overseeing a team of diverse professionals to design and construct residential building projects.
- Successfully helped clients outline their briefs and ensured construction within project timelines while helping clients stay within their budgets in a very dynamic cost environment without compromising quality standards.

DIRECTOR, BUSINESS DEVELOPMENT

Collaborations Integrated Systems Limited, Lagos, Nigeria

Nov 2008 - Jun 2020

- Co-founded an eLearning start-up that developed a Learning Management System solution which was successfully deployed in one of the major banks in Nigeria after meeting the expectations of the bank's rigorous internal audit checks for security, performance, reliance and accountability to serve over 3000 staff.
- Helped establish and maintain an exclusive partnership in Nigeria for Intuition, U.K, which has a library of the world's largest catalogue of globally relevant financial market e-learning. Identified eLearning content needs of clients and sold off-the-shelf eLearning content published by Intuition.

SOFTWARE TEST ANALYST

Result Group Ltd, Elland, West Yorkshire

Nov 2007-Sept 2008

- Studied design specifications, functional specifications and supporting documentation created by development / business users.
- Created test scripts and test cases and was involved in the manual running of test script and logging defects into the problem report form.
- Was sort out by Project Managers and developers within the company in testing features that involved complex charge calculations due to being very detailed and analytical whilst testing.

NETWORK SYSTEMS ANALYST

Tara Systems Limited Network (MetroNG) and Internet Service Provider, Lagos, Nigeria

Sept 2004-July 2005

- Served as a Technical Support Engineer where I resolved onsite, online and telephone technical support issues.
- Assisted senior engineers in the successful installation of outdoor fixed wireless, fibre, infrared and DSL solutions thereby providing dedicated bandwidth for corporate clients which included the BBC Nigeria, Haliburton and the Austrian Embassy.